<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="names">
        <item>Bistrița</item>
        <item>Brașov</item>
        <item>Cluj-Napoca</item>
        <item>Oradea</item>
        <item>Sibiu</item>
        <item>Sighișoara</item>
        <item>Biertan</item>
        <item>Câlnic</item>
        <item>Prejmer</item>
        <item>Saschiz</item>
        <item>Viscri</item>
        <item>Alba Iulia Citadel</item>
        <item>Bran Castle</item>
        <item>Corvin Castle</item>
        <item>Făgăraș Fortress</item>
        <item>Râșnov Citadel</item>
        <item>Peleș Castle</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="descriptions">
        <item>Bistrița is the capital city of Bistrița-Năsăud County, in northern Transylvania, Romania. It is situated on the Bistrița River. The city has a population of approximately 70,000 inhabitants, and it administers six villages.</item>
        <item>Brașov is a city in Romania and the administrative centre of Brașov County.
According to the latest Romanian census (2011), Brașov has a population of 253,200, making it the 7th most populous city in Romania. The metropolitan area is home to 369,896 residents.\n
Brașov is located in the central part of the country. It is surrounded by the Southern Carpathians and is part of the Transylvania region.\n
The city is notable for being an important centre of Transylvanian Saxons in the past, and a large commercial hub on the trade roads between East and West. It is also the birthplace of the national anthem of Romania.</item>
        <item>Cluj-Napoca, commonly known as Cluj, is the fourth most populous city in Romania, and the seat of Cluj County in the northwestern part of the country. Located in the Someșul Mic River valley, the city is considered the unofficial capital to the historical province of Transylvania. From 1790 to 1848 and from 1861 to 1867, it was the official capital of the Grand Principality of Transylvania.\n
Cluj-Napoca experienced a decade of decline during the 1990s, its international reputation suffering from the policies of its mayor at the time, Gheorghe Funar. Today, the city is one of the most important academic, cultural, industrial and business centres in Romania. Among other institutions, it hosts the country's largest university, Babeș-Bolyai University, with its famous botanical garden; nationally renowned cultural institutions; as well as the largest Romanian-owned commercial bank.Cluj-Napoca held the titles of European Youth Capital in 2015 and European City of Sport in 2018.</item>
        <item>Oradea the capital city of Bihor County and Crișana region, is one of the important centers of economic, social and cultural development in the western part of Romania, retaining these characteristics throughout history. The city is located in the north-west of Romania, nestled between hills on the Crișana plain, on the banks of Crișul Repede River, that divides the city into almost equal halves.</item>
        <item>Sibiu is a city in Transylvania, Romania, with a population of 147,245. Located some 275 km (171 mi) north-west of Bucharest, the city straddles the Cibin River, a tributary of the river Olt. Now the capital of Sibiu County, between 1692 and 1791 and 1849–65 Sibiu was the capital of the Principality of Transylvania.\n
Sibiu is one of the most important cultural centres of Romania and was designated the European Capital of Culture for the year 2007, along with the city of Luxembourg. Formerly the centre of the Transylvanian Saxons, the old city of Sibiu was ranked as "Europe's 8th-most idyllic place to live" by Forbes in 2008.</item>
        <item>Sighișoara is a city on the Târnava Mare River in Mureș County, Romania. Located in the historic region of Transylvania, Sighișoara has a population of 28,102 according to the 2011 census. It is a popular tourist destination for its well-preserved walled old town, which is listed by UNESCO as a World Heritage Site.\n
The city administers seven villages: Angofa, Aurel Vlaicu, Hetiur, Rora, Șoromiclea, Venchi and Viilor.</item>
        <item>Biertan is a commune in central Romania, in the north of the Sibiu County, 80 km north of Sibiu and 29 km east of Mediaş. Biertan is one of the most important Saxon villages with fortified churches in Transylvania, having been on the list of UNESCO World Heritage Sites since 1993. The Biertan fortified church was the see of the Lutheran Evangelical Bishop in Transylvania between 1572 and 1867.\n
The commune is composed of three villages: Biertan, Copșa Mare and Richiș, each of which has a fortified church.</item>
        <item>Câlnic is a commune in Alba County, Romania, composed of two villages, Câlnic and Deal. Câlnic village is known for its castle, which is on UNESCO's list of World Heritage Sites.
Câlnic Citadel, first mentioned in 1269, is very well preserved. Built as a noble's residence, it was bought in 1430 by local peasants and fortified. It consists of a large court surrounded by walls and some buildings adjacent to the walls. In the middle of the court there is a large donjon as well as a chapel. The castle differs from most other constructions of this type in that it is not situated on a hilltop but rather in a depression, much lower than the surrounding hills. This position, clearly inconvenient in case of a siege, can be explained by the castle's first function as a residence, not meant as a defensive construction.</item>
        <item>Prejmer is a commune in Brașov County, Romania. It is composed of three villages: Lunca Câlnicului, Prejmer and Stupinii Prejmerului. Located 18 km northeast of Brașov, the Olt River passes through the commune.\n
The Teutonic Knights constructed the fortress Tartlau in 1212–1213 as part of their colonization of the Burzenland region. The town of Prejmer near the castle had begun development by 1225, and was the eastern-most settlement of the Transylvanian Saxons. Prejmer was repeatedly invaded throughout the Middle Ages by various groups, including the Mongols, Tatars, Hungarians, Ottoman Turks, Cossacks, and Moldavians. However, the castle was only captured once, by Gabriel Báthory in 1611. Most of Prejmer's German population fled the commune after the Romanian Revolution of 1989.</item>
        <item>Saschiz is a commune in Mureș County, Romania. It has a population of 2,048: 88% Romanians, 5% Germans, 4% Hungarians and 3% Roma. It is composed of three villages: Cloașterf, Mihai Viteazu (Zoltan until 1932) and Saschiz.
Saschiz, with its 15th-century church, is part of the World Heritage Site Villages with fortified churches in Transylvania, designated in 1999 by UNESCO.</item>
        <item>Viscri's population is of Roma majority, with a few Romanians, and about 20 Germans. It lies northwest of Rupea and can be reached through Dacia on a 7 km unpaved road. The village is best known for the highly fortified Viscri fortified church, originally built around 1100. It is part of the villages with fortified churches in Transylvania, designated in 1993 as a World Heritage Site by UNESCO. The first documentation of Viscri is a record of church taxes dated around 1400, in which the village is referred to as being part of the Rupea parish. Its inhabitants consisted of 51 farmers, 1 school master, 3 shepherds and 2 paupers.\n
The origins of the fortified church date from 1100 when the Székelys built a small church with a single hall and semicircular apse. Around 1185 the church was taken over by Saxon colonists, and the Székelys were forced to settle further north. In the 14th century the eastern part of the church was rebuilt and in 1525, the first fortifications with towers were added. In the 18th century the church was surrounded by a second defense wall. After 1743 a covered corridor for the storage of corn was built. A century later, two chambers in the defense corridor of the bastion were turned into school rooms. The classic 19th-century altar has as centerpiece "the Blessing of the Children" by the painter J. Paukratz from Rupea. The font was made from a capital of the 13th-century church. To this day, the church is surrounded by a cemetery with gravestones dating back to the "Bijelo Brdo culture".\n
In 2006, The Prince of Wales bought and restored two 18th century Saxon houses in the Transylvanian villages of Mălâncrav and Viscri to help protect the unique way of life that has existed for hundreds of years and promote sustainable tourism. The buildings have been sensitively restored and converted into guest houses for tourists. They remain in keeping with the surrounding architecture and feature a number of Transylvanian antiques but with modern facilities where possible. The renovation of these buildings has helped provide a sustainable future for the people of rural Transylvania while also enabling residents to maintain their traditional way of life.</item>
        <item>The main historical area of Alba Iulia is the Upper Town region, developed by Charles VI, Holy Roman Emperor in honour of whom the Habsburgs renamed the city Karlsburg. The fortress, with seven bastions in a stellar shape, was constructed between 1716 and 1735 by two Swiss fortification architects. The first was Giovanni Morandi Visconti, who built two old Italian-style bastions. The second was Nicolaus Doxat de Demoret—nicknamed "Austrian Vauban". After 1720, the two architects radically transformed the medieval fortress shaped by the former Roman castrum into a seven-bastion baroque fortress, developing Menno van Coehorn's new Dutch system, of which the fortress of Alba Iulia is the best preserved example.</item>
        <item>Bran Castle, situated near Bran and in the immediate vicinity of Brașov, is a national monument and landmark in Romania. The fortress is situated on the border between Transylvania and Wallachia, on DN73. Commonly known as "Dracula's Castle" (although it is one among several locations linked to the Dracula legend, including Poenari Castle and Hunyadi Castle), it is often erroneously referred to as the home of the title character in Bram Stoker's Dracula. There is, however, no evidence that Stoker knew anything about this castle, which has only tangential associations with Vlad the Impaler, voivode of Wallachia, the putative inspiration for Dracula. Dutch author Hans Corneel de Roos, proposes as location for Castle Dracula an empty mountain top, Mount Izvorul Călimanului, 2,033 metres (6,670 ft) high, located in the Călimani Alps near the former border with Moldavia. Stoker's description of Dracula's crumbling fictional castle also bears no resemblance to Bran Castle.\n
The castle is now a museum dedicated to displaying art and furniture collected by Queen Marie. Tourists can see the interior on their own or by a guided tour. At the bottom of the hill is a small open-air museum park exhibiting traditional Romanian peasant structures (cottages, barns, etc.) from across the country.</item>
        <item>Corvin Castle, also known as Hunyadi Castle or Hunedoara Castle (Romanian: Castelul Huniazilor or Castelul Corvinilor; Hungarian: Vajdahunyadi vár), is a Gothic-Renaissance castle in Hunedoara, Romania. It is one of the largest castles in Europe and figures in a list of the seven wonders of Romania.</item>
        <item>Făgăraș, together with Amlaș, constituted during the Middle Ages a traditional Romanian local-autonomy region in Transylvania. The first written document mentioning Romanians in Transylvania referred to Vlach lands in the Făgăraș Region in 1222. After the Tatar invasion in 1241–1242, Saxons settled in the area. In 1369, Louis I of Hungary gave the Royal Estates of Făgăraș to his vassal, Vladislav I of Wallachia. As in other similar cases in medieval Europe (such as Foix, Pokuttia or Dauphiné), the local feudal had to swear oath of allegiance to the king for the specific territory, even when the former was himself an independent ruler of another state. Therefore, the region became the feudal property of the princes of Wallachia, but remained within the Kingdom of Hungary. The territory remained in the possession of Wallachian princes until 1464.</item>
        <item>Râșnov Citadel is a historic monument and landmark in Romania. It is situated in Râşnov, Brașov County, in the immediate vicinity of Brașov.\n
The citadel was built as part of a defence system for the Transylvanian villages exposed to outside invasions. A decisive aspect for building the citadel on the actual location was the route of the invading armies which were coming from the Bran pass and were passing through Râșnov, on their way to Burzenland. The only chance of survival for the inhabitants of the area, inclusively from Cristian and Ghimbav, was the refuge inside the citadel. Compelled to stay there for decades, the people of Râșnov and the nearby villages turned the fortification into a dwelling.</item>
        <item>Peleș Castle is a Neo-Renaissance castle in the Carpathian Mountains, near Sinaia, in Prahova County, Romania, on an existing medieval route linking Transylvania and Wallachia, built between 1873 and 1914. Its inauguration was held in 1883. It was constructed for King Carol I.
By form and function, Peleş is a palace, but it is consistently called a castle. Its architectural style is a romantically inspired blend Neo-Renaissance and Gothic Revival similar to Schloss Neuschwanstein in Bavaria. A Saxon influence can be observed in the interior courtyard facades, which have allegorical hand-painted murals and ornate fachwerk similar to that seen in northern European alpine architecture. Interior decoration is mostly Baroque influenced, with heavy carved woods and exquisite fabrics.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="read_more">
        <item>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bistrița</item>
        <item>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brașov</item>
        <item>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cluj-Napoca</item>
        <item>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oradea</item>
        <item>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sibiu</item>
        <item>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sighișoara</item>
        <item>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biertan</item>
        <item>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Câlnic,_Alba</item>
        <item>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prejmer</item>
        <item>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saschiz</item>
        <item>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bunești,_Brașov#Viscri</item>
        <item>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alba_Iulia#Landmarks</item>
        <item>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bran_Castle</item>
        <item>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Corvin_Castle</item>
        <item>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Făgăraș#History</item>
        <item>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Râșnov_Citadel</item>
        <item>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peleș_Castle</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="latitude">
        <item>47.1330456</item>
        <item>45.6525767</item>
        <item>46.7834818</item>
        <item>47.0746904</item>
        <item>45.7830954</item>
        <item>46.2230343</item>
        <item>46.1350388</item>
        <item>45.8877718</item>
        <item>45.7271051</item>
        <item>46.1943276</item>
        <item>46.0555767</item>
        <item>46.0616789</item>
        <item>45.5149059</item>
        <item>45.7493187</item>
        <item>45.8452535</item>
        <item>45.5906059</item>
        <item>45.3598294</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="longitude">
        <item>24.4766056</item>
        <item>25.5264233</item>
        <item>23.546473</item>
        <item>21.8674048</item>
        <item>24.0697987</item>
        <item>24.7761976</item>
        <item>24.5131588</item>
        <item>23.6467731</item>
        <item>25.7589085</item>
        <item>24.9532126</item>
        <item>25.0889325</item>
        <item>23.5229834</item>
        <item>25.364975</item>
        <item>22.8860879</item>
        <item>24.9716077</item>
        <item>25.4672354</item>
        <item>25.540516</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="zoom">
        <item>14</item>
        <item>12</item>
        <item>12</item>
        <item>12</item>
        <item>12</item>
        <item>14</item>
        <item>15</item>
        <item>15</item>
        <item>14</item>
        <item>15</item>
        <item>16</item>
        <item>15</item>
        <item>17</item>
        <item>17</item>
        <item>17</item>
        <item>17</item>
        <item>17</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="images">
        <item>bistrita</item>
        <item>brasov</item>
        <item>cluj_napoca</item>
        <item>oradea</item>
        <item>sibiu</item>
        <item>sighisoara</item>
        <item>biertan</item>
        <item>calnic</item>
        <item>prejmer</item>
        <item>saschiz</item>
        <item>viscri</item>
        <item>alba_iulia_citadel</item>
        <item>bran_castle</item>
        <item>corvin_castle</item>
        <item>fagaras_fortress</item>
        <item>rasnov_citadel</item>
        <item>peles_castle</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>